[
  {
    "question": "386. Which of these statements about driving in areas with strong winds is true?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Strong winds have no effect on driving.",
      "b. Winds are especially a problem when coming out of tunnels.",
      "c. Wind is always a tailwind and helps in driving."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Winds are especially a problem when coming out of tunnels."
  },
  {
    "question": "387. If a vehicle is loaded with too little weight on the drive axles, what can happen?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Better traction is achieved.",
      "b. The vehicle will have improved fuel efficiency.",
      "c. Poor traction."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Poor traction."
  },
  {
    "question": "388. What is counter steering?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Turning the steering wheel in the same direction as the skid.",
      "b. Not turning the steering wheel at all during a skid.",
      "c. Turning the steering wheel in the other direction after steering to avoid a hazard."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Turning the steering wheel in the other direction after steering to avoid a hazard."
  },
  {
    "question": "389. A skid happens whenever the tires:",
    "choices": [
      "a. Have excessive tread depth.",
      "b. Lose their grip on the road.",
      "c. Are properly inflated."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Lose their grip on the road."
  },
  {
    "question": "390. Which of these statements about cargo loading is true?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Federal regulations dictate legal weight limits.",
      "b. State regulations dictate legal weight limits.",
      "c. There are no regulations concerning cargo weight limits."
    ],
    "answer": "b. State regulations dictate legal weight limits."
  },
  {
    "question": "392. When a coolant container is part of a pressurized system, which of these is true?",
    "choices": [
      "a. You should never check the coolant level of a hot engine.",
      "b. You can check the coolant level of a hot engine.",
      "c. Coolant containers are never part of a pressurized system."
    ],
    "answer": "b. You can check the coolant level of a hot engine."
  },
  {
    "question": "393. You should avoid driving through deep puddles or flowing water. But if you must, which of these steps can help keep your brakes working?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Completely release the brakes while driving in water.",
      "b. Slam on the brakes to remove water from them.",
      "c. Gently put on the brakes while driving in water."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Gently put on the brakes while driving in water."
  },
  {
    "question": "394. Which of the below is NOT a characteristic of a front tire failure?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Rapid deflation of the tire.",
      "b. Loss of steering control.",
      "c. Deflated tire."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Deflated tire."
  },
  {
    "question": "395. Why will your vehicle's speed naturally increase on downgrades?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Because of increased engine power.",
      "b. Because brakes automatically disengage on downgrades.",
      "c. Because of gravity."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Because of gravity."
  },
  {
    "question": "396. Which of these pieces of emergency equipment should be carried in your vehicle?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Portable barbecue grill.",
      "b. Extra cushions for the seats.",
      "c. Warning devices for parked vehicles."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Warning devices for parked vehicles."
  },
  {
    "question": "398. You should signal continuously while turning because:",
    "choices": [
      "a. You need to conserve battery power.",
      "b. You need both hands on the wheel to turn safely.",
      "c. You need to keep the turn signal audible."
    ],
    "answer": "b. You need both hands on the wheel to turn safely."
  },
  {
    "question": "399. Most serious result from:",
    "choices": [
      "a. Driving too slowly for road conditions.",
      "b. Driving at night.",
      "c. Driving too fast for road conditions."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Driving too fast for road conditions."
  },
  {
    "question": "400. When you are parked at the side of the road at night, you must:",
    "choices": [
      "a. Turn off all your vehicle lights to save power.",
      "b. Use your high beams to warn other drivers.",
      "c. Turn on your emergency flashers to warn others."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Turn on your emergency flashers to warn others."
  },
  {
    "question": "401. You do NOT have the hazmat endorsement on your commercial driver's license. You can drive a vehicle hauling hazardous materials when:",
    "choices": [
      "a. You are driving within city limits.",
      "b. The vehicle does not require placards.",
      "c. You have a passenger endorsement."
    ],
    "answer": "b. The vehicle does not require placards."
  },
  {
    "question": "402. In your mirror, you see a car approaching from the rear. The next time you check your mirror, you do not see the car. You wish to change lanes, you should:",
    "choices": [
      "a. Wait to change lanes until you are sure the car is not in your blind spot.",
      "b. Change lanes immediately.",
      "c. Assume the car has passed and change lanes."
    ],
    "answer": "a. Wait to change lanes until you are sure the car is not in your blind spot."
  },
  {
    "question": "403. Whenever you double your speed, your vehicle has about_____ times the destructive powers if it crashes.",
    "choices": [
      "a. 2 . ",
      "b. 4 .",
      "c. 3 ."
    ],
    "answer": "b. 4 ."
  },
  {
    "question": "404. You are driving a new truck with a manual transmission. What gear will you probably have to use to take a long, steep downhill grade?",
    "choices": [
      "a. A higher gear than you would use to climb the hill.",
      "b. A lower gear than you would use to climb the hill.",
      "c. The same gear as you would use to climb the hill."
    ],
    "answer": "b. A lower gear than you would use to climb the hill."
  },
  {
    "question": "405. What should you do if you are unsure whether you have enough overhead clearance?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Keep driving and hope for the best.",
      "b. Proceed slowly and honk your horn continuously.",
      "c. Find another route that does not require driving under the object."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Find another route that does not require driving under the object."
  },
  {
    "question": "406. You are driving a heavy vehicle. You must exit a highway that uses an off-ramp that curves downhill. You should:",
    "choices": [
      "a. Slow down to a safe speed before the curve.",
      "b. Speed up to get ahead of other vehicles.",
      "c. Use your emergency brakes to slow down."
    ],
    "answer": "a. Slow down to a safe speed before the curve."
  },
  {
    "question": "407. You are driving a vehicle at 55 mph on dry pavement. About how much total stopping distance will you need to bring it to a stop?",
    "choices": [
      "a. The length of a football field (300 feet).",
      "b. Half the length of a football field (150 feet).",
      "c. A car length (15 feet)."
    ],
    "answer": "a. The length of a football field (300 feet)."
  },
  {
    "question": "408. On which fires can you use water?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Electrical fires.",
      "b. Tires.",
      "c. Fuel fires."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Tires."
  },
  {
    "question": "409. What is the term for a commercial vehicle's habit of swinging wide on turns?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Off-road driving.",
      "b. Tailgating.",
      "c. Off-tracking."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Off-tracking."
  },
  {
    "question": "410. Which of the following statements about backing is true?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Backing is always dangerous.",
      "b. You should use a helper and communicate with hand signals.",
      "c. You should back and turn toward the driver's side whenever possible.",
      "d. All of the above."
    ],
    "answer": "d. All of the above."
  },
  {
    "question": "411. Which of these statements about double clutching and shifting is true?",
    "choices": [
      "a. You should only double clutch when shifting into reverse.",
      "b. You can use the tachometer to tell when you shift.",
      "c. Double clutching is not necessary when shifting with an automatic transmission."
    ],
    "answer": "b. You can use the tachometer to tell when you shift."
  },
  {
    "question": "412. One reason that dry bulk tanks require special care is:",
    "choices": [
      "a. They are prone to leaking fuel.",
      "b. The load can shift.",
      "c. They are difficult to see at night."
    ],
    "answer": "b. The load can shift."
  },
  {
    "question": "413. 'Perception Distance' is the distance your vehicle travels from the time:",
    "choices": [
      "a. Your eyes see a hazard to the time your brain knows it's a hazard.",
      "b. Your brakes are applied to the time your vehicle comes to a complete stop.",
      "c. You hear a horn honking to the time you react to the sound."
    ],
    "answer": "a. Your eyes see a hazard to the time your brain knows it's a hazard."
  },
  {
    "question": "414. What is the first thing you should try to do if your brakes fail while driving downhill?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Apply the parking brake.",
      "b. Downshift to a lower gear.",
      "c. Get off the road as soon as possible."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Get off the road as soon as possible."
  },
  {
    "question": "415. Which of these may be a sign of tire failure?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Smooth, even tire wear.",
      "b. Wheels fishtailing.",
      "c. Proper tire inflation."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Wheels fishtailing."
  },
  {
    "question": "416. What should you do before driving in mountains?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Check your tire pressure.",
      "b. Know the escape ramp locations on the route.",
      "c. Test your horn."
    ],
    "answer": "b. Know the escape ramp locations on the route."
  },
  {
    "question": "417. Which of these statements about shipping hazardous materials is true?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Hazardous materials labels are not required on small containers.",
      "b. A four-inch, diamond-shaped hazardous materials label must be on the container.",
      "c. Hazardous materials are only shipped in specially designed containers."
    ],
    "answer": "b. A four-inch, diamond-shaped hazardous materials label must be on the container."
  },
  {
    "question": "418. Which of these systems should receive extra attention during a winter weather inspection?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Exhaust.",
      "b. Steering.",
      "c. Fuel system."
    ],
    "answer": "a. Exhaust."
  },
  {
    "question": "419. Truck escape ramps:",
    "choices": [
      "a. Are illegal to use.",
      "b. Are only found on steep mountain grades.",
      "c. Help avoid damage to vehicles."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Help avoid damage to vehicles."
  },
  {
    "question": "420. If someone is following you too closely (tailgating), you should:",
    "choices": [
      "a. Increase your speed to create more space.",
      "b. Ignore them and continue at your current speed.",
      "c. Increase your following distance."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Increase your following distance."
  },
  {
    "question": "421. You are performing a pre-trip inspection on your brakes and suspension system. Which of these statements is true?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Brake drums should be covered in oil or grease for proper lubrication.",
      "b. Brake drums should have loose parts for flexibility.",
      "c. Brake drums should not have oil or grease on them."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Brake drums should not have oil or grease on them."
  },
  {
    "question": "422. Which of these is NOT a part of the engine compartment pre-trip inspection?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Battery connections.",
      "b. Power steering fluid level.",
      "c. Valve clearance."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Valve clearance."
  },
  {
    "question": "423. You are required to stop at a railroad grade crossing when:",
    "choices": [
      "a. You are transporting hazardous materials.",
      "b. The cargo makes a stop mandatory under state or federal regulations.",
      "c. The crossing gates are up."
    ],
    "answer": "b. The cargo makes a stop mandatory under state or federal regulations."
  },
  {
    "question": "424. Which of these items should be tested when the vehicle is stopped?",
    "choices": [
      "a. Windshield wipers.",
      "b. Clutch performance.",
      "c. Service brake."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Service brake."
  },
  {
    "question": "425. Most serious skids result from:",
    "choices": [
      "a. Sudden acceleration.",
      "b. Turning the steering wheel too much.",
      "c. Driving too fast for conditions."
    ],
    "answer": "c. Driving too fast for conditions."
  },
  {
    "question": "426. Which of these statements is true about mirror adjustment?",
    "choices": [
      "a. You should adjust your mirrors before you start a trip.",
      "b. You should adjust your mirrors while driving to ensure they are still aligned.",
      "c. You should only adjust your mirrors when stopped at a rest area."
    ],
    "answer": "a. You should adjust your mirrors before you start a trip."
  },
  {
    "question": "427. For a first offense of driving a commercial vehicle under the influence of alcohol or drugs, you will lose your CDL for at least:",
    "choices": ["6 months", "1 year", "2 years"],
    "answer": "1 year"
  },
  {
    "question": "428. You must complete a written vehicle inspection report each day. You must sign the report:",
    "choices": [
      "Only when defects noted are certified repaired.",
      "At the beginning of each trip.",
      "Every time you refuel."
    ],
    "answer": "Only when defects noted are certified repaired."
  },
  {
    "question": "429. Placards must be:",
    "choices": [
      "Placed on all four sides of a vehicle.",
      "Used to communicate the risk.",
      "Both A and B."
    ],
    "answer": "Both A and B."
  },
  {
    "question": "430. Why is a broken exhaust system dangerous?",
    "choices": [
      "It can cause the engine to overheat.",
      "It can reduce fuel efficiency.",
      "Poisonous fumes could enter the cab or sleeper berth."
    ],
    "answer": "Poisonous fumes could enter the cab or sleeper berth."
  },
  {
    "question": "431. If you have a heavy load that is slowing you down on an upgrade, you should:",
    "choices": [
      "Downshift to a higher gear.",
      "Downshift to a lower gear.",
      "Shift into neutral."
    ],
    "answer": "Shift into a lower gear."
  },
  {
    "question": "432. Which of these is a good thing to do when steering to avoid a crash?",
    "choices": [
      "Turn the steering wheel as far as it will go.",
      "Don't turn any more than needed to clear what is in your way.",
      "Swerve quickly to the opposite side of the road."
    ],
    "answer": "Don't turn any more than needed to clear what is in your way."
  },
  {
    "question": "433. How far should a driver look ahead of the vehicle while driving?",
    "choices": ["2-3 seconds", "5-7 seconds", "12-15 seconds"],
    "answer": "12-15 seconds"
  },
  {
    "question": "434. The engine braking effect is greatest when the engine is _____ the governed RPM and the transmission is in the_____gears.",
    "choices": ["near: lower", "Highest gear", "Lower gears"],
    "answer": "near: lower"
  },
  {
    "question": "435. Retarders:",
    "choices": [
      "Can cause the drive wheels to spin.",
      "Can cause the drive wheels to skid when they have poor traction.",
      "Have no effect on the vehicle's speed."
    ],
    "answer": "Can cause the drive wheels to skid when they have poor traction."
  },
  {
    "question": "436. Which of these is the proper way to signal to change lanes?",
    "choices": [
      "Signal briefly and make a rapid lane change.",
      "Signal early before you turn, and change lanes slowly and smoothly.",
      "Change lanes without signaling to avoid giving notice to other drivers."
    ],
    "answer": "Signal early before you turn, and change lanes slowly and smoothly."
  }
]
